<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 14, 2018</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03521479</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P2c</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03521479</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 2, Muti-Center Study of Repeat Dosing of Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester in Subjects With Herpes Labialis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Muti-Center Study of Repeat Dosing of Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester in Subjects With Herpes Labialis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Squarex, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Squarex, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objective: To assess local and generalized adverse events with repeat topical
      application of 2% and 0.5% squaric acid dibutyl ester (SADBE) in subjects with frequent
      herpes labialis (4 or more episodes in the previous 12 months).

      Secondary Objective: To assess efficacy of repeat topical application of 2% and 0.5% SADBE in
      the prevention of herpes labialis episodes.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary oral infection with the herpes simplex virus (HSV) typically occurs at a young age,
      is asymptomatic, and is not associated with significant morbidity. After primary oral
      infection, HSV may persist in a latent state in the trigeminal ganglion and later reactivate
      as the more common herpes labialis, or &quot;cold sores.&quot; Common triggers for reactivation are
      well known and include ultraviolet light, trauma, fatigue, stress, fever, inflammation, and
      menstruation. These lesions affect up to 45 percent of the U.S. population. They classically
      manifest as a well-localized cluster of small vesicles along the vermilion border of the lip
      or adjacent skin. The vesicles subsequently rupture, ulcerate, and crust within 24 to 48
      hours. Spontaneous healing occurs over seven to 10 days.

      In immunocompetent patients, herpes labialis usually is mild and self-limited. However, pain,
      swelling, and cosmetic concerns may prompt physician consultation. Orally administered
      antiviral agents, such as acyclovir (Zovirax) or valacyclovir (Valtrex), have a modest
      clinical benefit if initiated during the prodrome. Topical treatment with 1% penciclovir
      cream (Denavir) may reduce healing time and pain slightly, even if initiated after the
      prodrome. However, reduction in healing time with systemic or topical agents is modest.

      Squaric acid dibutyl ester (SADBE) is a topical immunotherapeutic agent used in the treatment
      of verruca vulgaris and alopecia areata. During a recent FDA Compounding Advisory Committee
      Meeting, it was recommended that squaric acid dibutylester be included on the list of bulk
      drug substances allowed for use in compounding under section 503A of the Federal Food, Drug,
      and Cosmetic Act. And SADBE has now been so listed under section 503A.

      A study completed by Lee et al of 29 patients with recalcitrant warts demonstrated complete
      clearance in 69% of patients with application every 2-4 weeks. Silverberg et al showed a
      complete clearance in 58% of patients (n=61) when SADBE was applied 3 times weekly. A
      placebo-controlled clinical study completed at Massachusetts General Hospital showed that
      squaric acid prevented recurrence of herpetic lesions. The effect of SADBE of delaying new
      herpes labialis outbreaks was highly significant (p&lt;0.01) as compared to placebo.

      Primary Objective: To assess local and generalized adverse events with repeat topical
      application of 2% and 0.5% squaric acid dibutyl ester (SADBE) in subjects with frequent
      herpes labialis (4 or more episodes in the previous 12 months).

      Secondary Objective: To assess efficacy of repeat topical application of 2% and 0.5% SADBE in
      the prevention of herpes labialis episodes.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 12, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Subjects will receive on a double blind basis one of two treatment regimens:
Group A: 15 subjects, treated with 2% SADBE on day 0 and with 2% SADBE on the visits at week 3, week 6, week 9, and month 8.
Group B: 15 subjects, treated with 2% SADBE on day 0 and with 0.5% SADBE on the visits at week 3, week 6, week 9, and month 8.
And subjects will be recruited on an open label basis to two other treatment regimens:
Group C: 15 subjects, treated with 2% SADBE on day 0, month 3, and month 6.
Group D: 15 subjects, treated with 2% SADBE on day 0 and month 6.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The double-blinding only applies between groups A and B. Subjects for groups C and D will be recruited on an open label basis.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Local and generalized adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess local and generalized adverse events with repeat topical application of 2% and 0.5% squaric acid dibutyl ester (SADBE) in subjects with frequent herpes labialis (4 or more episodes in the previous 12 months).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of repeat topical application.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess efficacy of repeat topical application of 2% and 0.5% SADBE in the prevention of herpes labialis episodes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Herpes Labialis</condition>
  <condition>HSV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treated with 2% Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester (SADBE) on day 0 and with 2% SADBE on the visits at week 3, week 6, week 9, and month 8.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treated with 2% Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester (SADBE) on day 0 and with 0.5% SADBE on the visits at week 3, week 6, week 9, and month 8.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treated with 2% Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester (SADBE) on day 0, month 3, and month 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group D</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treated with 2% Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester (SADBE) on day 0 and month 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Squaric Acid Dibutyl Ester</intervention_name>
    <description>Repeat topical application of 2% and 0.5% squaric acid dibutyl ester (SADBE) in subjects with frequent herpes labialis (4 or more episodes in the previous 12 months).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group D</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Repeat Dosing</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Age ≥ 18 and ≤ 65

          2. Clinical diagnosis of herpes labialis, which may be made at the screening visit based
             on the patient's self-reported history of symptoms. An active herpes labialis outbreak
             at the time of entry into the clinical trial will neither be required nor will be an
             exclusion criterion.

          3. Self report having four (4) or more episodes of herpes labialis in the past 12 months.

             Subjects will NOT be told that four-or-more episodes in the previous 12 months is the
             entry criterion. Subjects will be asked &quot;How many separate episodes of cold sores have
             you had in the previous 12 months?&quot; They will be included if they give an answer of
             four or more and excluded if they give an answer of three or fewer.

          4. At least half of the subject's episodes of the previous 12 months should be vesicular
             in nature and at least half preceded by prodromal symptoms. Prodromal symptoms may
             include tingling, itching, burning or pain before the development of a herpetic
             lesion.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Pregnant or lactating females.

          2. Current or recurrent non-herpetic infection or any underlying condition that may
             predispose to infection or anyone who has been admitted to the hospital due to
             bacteremia, pneumonia or any other serious infection in the last 12 months.

          3. Therapy with glucocorticoid or immunosuppressants at time of recruitment or within
             past 4 weeks prior to the screening visit, or at any time during the study (including
             inhaled corticosteroids for asthma), except for topical steroids in sites other than
             face.

          4. History of malignancy (except patients with surgically cured basal cell or squamous
             cell skin cancers).

          5. History of organ transplantation.

          6. HIV-positive status determined by history at screening or known history of any other
             immunosuppressive disease.

          7. Severe co-morbidities (CHF [NYHA class II or worse], MI, CVA or TIA) within 3 months
             of screening visit, current unstable angina pectoris or oxygen-dependent severe
             pulmonary disease.

          8. Known hypersensitivity to Dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO).

          9. Any condition judged by the investigator to cause this clinical trial to be
             detrimental to the patient.

         10. Subject is currently enrolled in another investigational device or drug trial(s), or
             subject has received other investigational agent(s) within 28 days of the screening
             visit.

         11. Previous exposure to SADBE (squaric acid or squaric acid dibutyl ester).

         12. Subject has an abnormal skin condition (e.g., acne, eczema, rosacea, psoriasis,
             albinism, or chronic vesiculo-bullous disorder) that occurs in the area ordinarily
             affected by herpes labialis

         13. Subject has an abnormal skin condition (e.g., eczema, rosacea, psoriasis, albinism, or
             chronic vesiculo-bullous disorder) that occurs in the inner aspect of either upper arm
             (the area where drug will be applied).

         14. Subject has had a vaccine for either HSV-1 or HSV-2.

         15. Subject has had treatment with anti-viral therapy (including ABREVA) within 2 weeks
             before first dose of SADBE or at any time during the study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>International Research Partners, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Doral</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33166</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Luis Aponte, MD</last_name>
      <phone>305-468-9455</phone>
      <email>laponte@iresearchpartners.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Milagros Agosto, MS, CCRC</last_name>
      <phone>305-468-9455</phone>
      <email>magosto@iresearchpartners.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Luis Aponte, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Danai Pino, FMD, CRC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Noris Leyva, FMD, CRC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Milagros Agosto, MS, CCRC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lisa Fuentes, BA, CRC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria Cisneros, BS, CRC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prism Clinical Research, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Paul</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mark A Matson, MD</last_name>
      <phone>651-651-2924</phone>
      <email>mmatson@prismresearchinc.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Charles Halstenson</last_name>
      <phone>651-641-2915</phone>
      <email>chalstenson@prismresearchinc.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Charles E Halstenson, PharmD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karen E Karn, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shannon M Canas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sam Gillund, CCRC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark A Matson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2018</verification_date>
  <!-- For several months we've had both old and new date name tags                             -->
  <!-- Now, the old date names have been dropped.                                               -->
  <!-- The new date name replacements are:                                                      -->
  <!--     OLD (gone)                                        NEW (in use)                       -->
  <!--   lastchanged_date                         becomes   last_update_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_date                       becomes   study_first_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_date               becomes   results_first_submitted             -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_disposition_date   becomes   disposition_first_submitted         -->
  <study_first_submitted>April 29, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 29, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 10, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 29, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 29, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 10, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Squaric Acid</keyword>
  <keyword>SADBE</keyword>
  <keyword>Squaric acid dibutyl ester</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Herpes Labialis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Squaric acid dibutyl ester</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>
