<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on August 08, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01341288</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08F.298</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2007-24</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>R01CA091763</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01341288</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Robotic Seed Implantation for Prostate Cancer Brachytherapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>EUCLIDIAN</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase I Study Using EUCLIDIAN Robotic Assistance During Prostate Brachytherapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sidney Kimmel Cancer Center at Thomas Jefferson University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Thomas Jefferson University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>No</is_unapproved_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A robotic brachytherapy device will be used to assist physicians in performing seed
      implantation to the prostate. EUCLIDIAN is the first robotic system designed to allow
      automatic placement of radioactive seeds by robot and thus reduce operator dependence. The
      clinical study is designed to evaluate the dosimetric quality, accuracy and patient
      self-reported quality of life scores after robotic brachytherapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      EUCLIDIAN (Endo-Uro Computed Lattice for Intratumoral Delivery, Implantation, Ablation with
      Nanosensing)

      The dose-volume histogram parameters of robotic brachytherapy will be compared to historical
      controls of the study institution. Short-term (&lt;1 yr) health-related quality of life (HRQoL)
      and changes will be assessed using FACT-P and IPSS self-report questionnaires.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Slow accrual
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 29, 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 27, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 26, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Coverage of the prostate by the prescribed radiation dose at V100</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 and Day 30 post-implant</time_frame>
    <description>The principal endpoint is the dose-volume histogram (DVH) measured at V100 (percent volume of the target receiving the intended dose). These values will also be compared retrospectively to those in the conventional group. Improved quality will be demonstrated by increased V100 in the protocol patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coverage of the prostate by the prescribed radiation dose at D90</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary endpoint is the dose-volume histogram (DVH) measured at D90 (dose to 90% of the target volume). These values will also be compared retrospectively to those in the conventional group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Prostate (FACT-P)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient self-reported, health-related, quality of life measures using the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Prostate (FACT-P) self-report questionnaire. FACT-P instruments prior to treatment (T0), 1 month (T1), 3 months (T3), 6 months (T6) and 12 months (T12) following treatment with robot-assisted brachytherapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient self-reported, health-related, quality of life measures using the International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS) self-report questionnaire. IPSS instruments prior to treatment (T0), 1 month (T1), 3 months (T3), 6 months (T6) and 12 months (T12) following treatment with robot-assisted brachytherapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Implant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Robotic implantation of brachytherapy seeds to treat prostate cancer</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EUCLIDIAN Robot</intervention_name>
    <description>EUCLIDIAN (Endo-Uro Computed Lattice for Intratumoral Delivery, Implantation, Ablation with Nanosensing) system for placement of radioactive seeds in the prostate</description>
    <arm_group_label>Implant</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Endo-Uro Computed Lattice for Intratumoral Delivery, Implantation, Ablation with Nanosensing</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically confirmed, adenocarcinoma of the prostate, clinical stage T1c-T2b, NX,
             N0, M0.

          -  Zubrod status 0-1.

          -  Prostate tumor biopsy grading by Gleason score classification is mandatory prior to
             registration

          -  No prior pelvic radiation or chemotherapy for any reason; induction hormonal therapy
             beginning &lt; or = 6 months prior to registration is acceptable.

          -  Prostate volume &lt; or = 65 cc prior to registration, or planned use of LHRH agonist
             therapy for reduction of prostate volume. If LHRH agonist therapy is used to reduce
             prostate volume, then prostate volume must be &lt; or = 65 cc on the routine pre-implant
             volume study to be eligible for the study.

          -  Gleason score 6, or Gleason Score 7 if both , or = 33% of biopsy cores contain cancer
             and PSA level is &lt; or = 10 ng/mL.

          -  AUA voiding symptoms score &lt; or = 15.

          -  Prostate specific antigen (PSA) prior to study entry (and prior to any hormone
             treatment if given); must be &lt; or = 20 ng/ml.

          -  Patients must sign a study-specific consent form prior to registration (Standard of
             care: only the standard consent form must be signed).

          -  Patient must be &gt; or = 40 years old.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Stage T2c, T3 or T4 disease.

          -  Lymph node involvement (pathological N1)

          -  Evidence of distant metastases (M1)

          -  Gleason score 8-10.

          -  Prostate specific antigen (PSA) prior to study entry &gt; 20 ng/mL.

          -  AUA voiding symptoms score &gt; 15.

          -  Radical surgery for carcinoma of the prostate.

          -  Previous hormonal therapy beginning &gt; 6 months prior to registration

          -  Previous or concurrent cancers other than basal or squamous cell skin cancers unless
             disease- free for &gt; or = 5 years.

          -  Major medical or psychiatric illness which, in the investigator's opinion, would
             prevent completion of treatment and would interfere with follow-up and/or completion
             of HRQoL questionnaires (not a condition for ineligibility in Standard of care).

          -  Prior TURP

          -  Hip prosthesis
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adam Dicker, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Thomas Jefferson University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomas Jefferson University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.KimmelCancerCenter.org</url>
    <description>Kimmel Cancer Center at Thomas Jefferson University, an NCI-Designated Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.JeffersonHospital.org</url>
    <description>Thomas Jefferson University Hospitals</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Podder TK, Buzurovic I, Huang K, Showalter T, Dicker AP, Yu Y. Reliability of EUCLIDIAN: an autonomous robotic system for image-guided prostate brachytherapy. Med Phys. 2011 Jan;38(1):96-106.</citation>
    <PMID>21361179</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 10, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 29, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>EUCLIDIAN</keyword>
  <keyword>Endo-Uro Computed Lattice for Intratumoral Delivery, Implantation, Ablation with Nanosensing</keyword>
  <keyword>robot</keyword>
  <keyword>brachytherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>seed implantation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>