<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 11, 2018</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02798588</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>69HCL15_0669</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02798588</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving Awakening Prognostication After Non Anoxic Coma Using PET-MRI in Intensive Care Unit</brief_title>
  <acronym>ETIC</acronym>
  <official_title>Improving Awakening Prognostication After Non Anoxic Coma Using PET-MRI in Intensive Care Unit</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospices Civils de Lyon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospices Civils de Lyon</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In last decades, several advances in the neuro-intensive management have lead to decrease
      mortality in Intensive Care Units. A significant morbidity remains as patients survive after
      a traumatic coma with uncertain quality of awakening and a high risk of functional
      disability. Predicting awareness recovery and functional disability of those who will awake
      constitutes a major challenge to inform patients' relatives, to give the best chances in
      terms of rehabilitation resources or to adapt intensive cares to a reasonable level. Tools
      currently available are not sufficient neither to predict bad awakening outcome nor to
      predict good functional outcome. In many countries, life's support cessation is a constant
      call for robust evaluation as soon as possible in ICU but it is mandatory to reach a positive
      predictive value of non-awaking close to 100%. Many clinical, electro-physiological,
      biological, radiological and functional parameters have been conducted with comatose patients
      assuming the purpose to predict outcome. Regarding unfavourable outcome, the gold standard is
      the abolition of the N20 component of somatosensory evoked potentials but the specificity is
      high enough only for patients with anoxic coma. Several neurophysiological markers such as
      MMN, P300 are correlated to a favourable outcome but the sensitivity and specificity remains
      low for patients who suffered a severe traumatic brain injury. New Diffusion Tensor imaging
      sequences provide complementary information to detect small structural lesions (diffuse
      axonal lesions). Recently, functional MRI analyzing Resting State has also been proposed as a
      prognostic marker during coma. PET using Fluoro-Desoxy-Glucose is able to assess the
      metabolism in key regions of the awakening network in either anaesthesia or sleep. Recent
      studies have reported interesting results at the chronic stage but to knowledge, these tools
      have only been used to address pathophysiology's issues and never to improve coma prognosis
      at the initial stage. The investigators hypothesize that the heterogeneity of the population
      requires a global and accurate assessment of the central nervous system, combining
      structural, metabolic and functional information in order to refine the prognosis.

      The protocol integrates in one-sequence most radiological markers of brain injury within a
      unique PET-MRI in Lyon. The most relevant originality of the study consists in confronting
      FDG-PET and MRI sequences to a large clinical, electrophysiological and biological battery.
      The added clinical value would be to question the synergistic effect of each parameter and to
      find out which ones are the most useful for awakening prediction, as they have not been
      compared in a multi-parametric database.

      PET-MRI, as a new device combining physiological and prognostic questioning, allows us:

        -  to implement a more integrative physio-pathological analysis

        -  to avoid the cofounding effect of awareness' fluctuations in recording simultaneously
           multiple functional imaging techniques.

      The RS will be analyzed at 2 epochs in order to assess the stability of brain connectivity,
      related to neuronal activity (glucose metabolism) and brain perfusion.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 16, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 16, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 16, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of feasibility (pilot study) with Number of patients included during a 12-months period</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of feasibility (pilot study) with ratio of patient included vs patient admissible according to the screening</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of feasibility (pilot study) with respect of deadline for completion of PET MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of security (pilot study) with tolerance of the PET-MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Unfavorable clinical evolution towards awareness (dichotomic criteria : absence of awareness with functional communication)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Building a prognostic tool including miscellaneous parameters (clinical, biological, electrophysiological, metabolic PET and multimodal MRI) for the prediction of an unfavourable outcome (death, vegetative state, minimally conscious state) at 1 year after a non-anoxic brain injury (focal or multifocal; either traumatic or vascular causes)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Unfavorable clinical evolution in absence of awareness (ordinal criteria within unfavorable outcome) with Coma Recovery Scale-Revised</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Defining an association of criteria, which are available in the 1st month after coma, that are able to predict at 1 year with a high positive predictive value the level of disorder of consciousness in the subgroup with unfavourable outcome in analyzing (according to Coma Recovery Scale-Revised) the evolution of :
vegetative state patients
minimally-conscious patients
dead patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional clinical evolution in presence of awareness (ordinal criteria within favorable outcome) according to Glasgow Outcome Scale (GOS)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Defining an association of criteria which are available in the 1st month after coma, that are able to predict at 1 year with a high positive predictive value the quality of functional outcome in the subgroup with favourable outcome in analyzing the level of autonomy according to Glasgow Outcome Scale (GOS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Coma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Comatose patients in ICU</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PET-MRI</intervention_name>
    <description>18Fluoro-Desoxy-Glucose's infusion for PET (glucose neural metabolism assessment, with quantitative information permitted by radioactivity monitoring through arterial catheter ; dosage = 1,5 MBq/Kg + 18,5 MBq as loading dose 5 min= Outside the scanner, Installation and movement management: Curare+/- sedative injection with standardized routine care protocol 10 min= Outside the scanner, Starting PET continuous acquisitionT= 0, Morphological MRI sequences- 3DT1, 3DFlair, T2SE, T2 HR on brainstem, Susceptibility and simple Diffusion Weighted Imaging-Specifically dedicated MR sequences based upon clinical issues 25 min, MRI in Resting state N°1 (global short-term functional connectivity)13 min, MRI DTI acquisition, 64 directions, sensitive to white matter injury 8 min, IRM in 2D-Arterial Spin Labelling:Quantitative Cerebral blood flow information (no Gadolinium)-&gt;8 min, IRM in Resting state 2 (repeated occurrence to assess stationarity) 13 min, End of PET continuous acquisition</description>
    <arm_group_label>Comatose patients in ICU</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Patients presenting either vascular or traumatic lesions

          2. Patients with no response to simple command 48h after sedation's cessation

          3. Patients included between 7 days (to reduce the effect of early oedema) and 30 days
             after the coma (to control the homogeneity of our cohort)

          4. Patients included between 18 and 75 years old, to limit the risk of care withdrawal
             for poor previous medical condition

          5. Patients evaluated by a global electrophysiological assessment at beside in ICU in a
             short delay before or after PET-MRI

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Patient with an associated anoxic encephalopathy

          2. Patients with contra-indication to MRI

          3. Patients with hypersensibility to the active molecules (FDG) or to one of this
             excipient

          4. Pregnant women

          5. Minor patients

          6. Patients under legal protection

          7. Patients not affiliated to French health care system

          8. Patients in poor medical condition (hemodynamic, respiratory instability)

          9. Patients moribund or with previous decision of care withdrawal

         10. Absence of relatives to give written consent
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Florent GOBERT, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Réanimation polyvalente neurologique Hospices Civils de Lyon</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Florent GOBERT, MD</last_name>
    <phone>04 72 68 12 96</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>florent.gobert01@chu-lyon.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Réanimation polyvalente neurologique Hôpital Neurologique HCL</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bron</city>
        <zip>69500</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Florent GOBERT, MD</last_name>
      <phone>04 72 68 12 96</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>florent.gobert01@chu-lyon.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Frédéric DAILLER, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jacques LUAUTE, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nathalie ANDRE-OBADIA, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Florent GOBERT, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2018</verification_date>
  <!-- For several months we've had both old and new date name tags                             -->
  <!-- Now, the old date names have been dropped.                                               -->
  <!-- The new date name replacements are:                                                      -->
  <!--     OLD (gone)                                        NEW (in use)                       -->
  <!--   lastchanged_date                         becomes   last_update_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_date                       becomes   study_first_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_date               becomes   results_first_submitted             -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_disposition_date   becomes   disposition_first_submitted         -->
  <study_first_submitted>May 27, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 8, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 14, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>coma</keyword>
  <keyword>prognosis</keyword>
  <keyword>comparative study</keyword>
  <keyword>functional imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>PET-MRI</keyword>
  <keyword>electrophysiology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>
