<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 19, 2019</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00001177</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>810126</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>81-M-0126</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00001177</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Premenstrual Syndrome and Premenstrual Dysphoria</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Evaluation of Women With Menstrually Regulated Mood and Behavioral Disorders</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to identify and describe the symptoms of premenstrual syndrome
      (PMS).

      Women who experience PMS symptoms will complete clinical interviews, self-rating scales, and
      evaluations of mood and endocrine function. A subgroup of women with severe PMS (Premenstrual
      Dysphoric Disorder or PMDD) will be offered additional research studies that focus on: 1)
      identifying the endocrine changes that may be responsible for changes in mood and behavior
      during the premenstrual period, 2) evaluating treatments for PMS symptoms, and/or 3)
      identifying genetic factors in women with and without PMS. Women with recurrent brief
      depression will also be recruited to serve as a comparison group.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The relevance of changes in ovarian steroids in the pathophysiology of menstrually-regulated
      mood disorders (MRMD [the term Premenstrual Dysphoria (PMD) will be employed in the text
      instead of MRMD] remains to be fully characterized. The purpose of this protocol is to allow
      for the careful screening of patients and healthy volunteers for participation in research
      protocols that examine the role of gonadal steroids in PMD and for the collection of natural
      history data. Women in this protocol will undergo an evaluation which may include: a
      psychiatric interview; a diagnostic interview; daily symptom rating scales; a medical
      history; a physical exam; blood and urine laboratory evaluation; and a request for medical
      records. The data collected may also be linked with data from other PMD protocols (e.g., DNA,
      psychophysiology tests, treatment studies, etc.) for the purposes of better understanding the
      diagnosis, pathophysiology, and treatment response of women with PMD. Upon conclusion of the
      evaluation process, subjects will either be offered participation in a research protocol and
      will sign the appropriate informed consent, or will be considered not appropriate for
      participation in research and will be referred back into the community.

      Finally, we wish to identify a group of women with recurrent brief depression, who will serve
      as an additional control group for the patients with menstrual cycle-related mood disorders.
      This protocol, then, serves as a screening and evaluation protocol to recruit subjects who
      are characterized with standard measures in this protocol and then offered participation in
      related studies.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 24, 1981</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1600</enrollment>
  <condition>PMS</condition>
  <condition>Premenstrual Mood Disorder</condition>
  <condition>PMDD</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:

        The subjects of this study will be women who meet the following criteria:

          -  history within the last two years of at least six months with menstrually-related mood
             or behavioral disturbances of at least moderate severity - that is, disturbances that
             are distinct in appearance and associated with a notable degree of subjective
             distress;

          -  a 30% increase in mean negative mood ratings (relative to the range of the scale
             employed) in the premenstrual week compared with the week following the end of menses
             in at least two of three cycles;

          -  age 18 to 50;

          -  not pregnant and in good medical health;

          -  regular menses.

        Subjects who do not meet the criteria listed above but who do meet diagnostic criteria for
        recurrent brief depression will also be studied. The criteria for recurrent brief
        depression include the following:

          -  dysphoric mood or loss of interest or pleasure;

          -  duration less than two weeks;

          -  four of the following symptoms: poor appetite or significant weight loss (when not
             dieting) or increased appetite or significant weight gain; insomnia or hypersomnia;
             psychomotor agitation or retardation; loss of interest or pleasure in usual
             activities, or decrease in sexual drive; loss of energy; fatigue; feelings of
             worthlessness, self-reproach, or excessive or inappropriate guilt; diminished ability
             to think or concentrate, slowed thinking, or indecisiveness;

          -  impairment in usual occupational activities;

          -  at least one-two episodes per month over one year.

        Age-matched women without mood and behavioral disorders will be recruited.

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:

        Subjects should have no general medical illness that is primary (i.e., appears to be
        causing the mood disorder);

        Current alcohol or substance use or dependence (excluding nicotine) of sufficient magnitude
        to require independent, concurrent treatment intervention (e.g., antabuse or opiate
        treatment, but not including self-help groups).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter J Schmidt, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peter J Schmidt, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-6120</phone>
    <email>peterschmidt@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_1981-M-0126.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rubinow DR. The premenstrual syndrome. New views. JAMA. 1992 Oct 14;268(14):1908-12.</citation>
    <PMID>1404717</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schmidt PJ, Nieman LK, Danaceau MA, Adams LF, Rubinow DR. Differential behavioral effects of gonadal steroids in women with and in those without premenstrual syndrome. N Engl J Med. 1998 Jan 22;338(4):209-16.</citation>
    <PMID>9435325</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bancroft J. The premenstrual syndrome--a reappraisal of the concept and the evidence. Psychol Med. 1993;Suppl 24:1-47. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>7906420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 27, 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 1999</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 1999</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 4, 1999</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 18, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 18, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">April 19, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Mood</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognition</keyword>
  <keyword>Menstrual</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuroendocrine</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetics</keyword>
  <keyword>PMDD</keyword>
  <keyword>PMS Premenstrual Syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>MRMD Menstrually Related Mood Disorder</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Premenstrual Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>
