<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 15, 2018</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03446690</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1135815</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03446690</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MI Varnish for the Prevention of White Spot Lesions</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Use of MI Varnish for the Prevention and Reduction of White Spot Lesions in Orthodontic Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The current study aimed to determine if MI Varnish has an effect in preventing the formation
      of white spot lesions for patients undergoing orthodontic treatment. 33 subjects were
      prospectively recruited for the project as the MI Varnish group, with a control group of 29
      orthodontically treated subjects who received routine treatment and oral hygiene
      regimes.Difference in prevention of white spot formation between the control and the study
      groups were evaluated through photographic records and clinical examination by using the
      Enamel Decalcification Index (EDI) scores.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Orthodontists face two common iatrogenic treatment side effects, root resorption and enamel
      decalcification, with the latter occurring at a much higher frequency. While the processes
      that lead to enamel demineralization are understood, methods to diminish or perhaps eliminate
      degradation of enamel surfaces are being searched for. A new product, MI Varnish, is current
      available and has been shown in some initial case reports to be useful in reducing white spot
      lesions. It contains a special milk-derived protein RECALDENT TM (CPP-ACP) in which the
      casein phosphopeptides (CPP) bind to teeth, dentin, and oral mucosa while the amorphous
      calcium phosphate (ACP) releases calcium and phosphate. The current study aimed to determine
      if MI Varnish has an effect in preventing the formation of white spot lesions for patients
      undergoing orthodontic treatment. 33 subjects were prospectively recruited for the project as
      the MI Varnish group, with a control group of 29 orthodontically treated subjects who
      received routine treatment and oral hygiene regimes. The study group received the MI Varnish
      on the day of bracket bonding. Subjects were recalled initially for 4 weeks (twice) and then
      at 3 monthly intervals. Difference in prevention of white spot formation between the control
      and the study groups were evaluated through photographic records and clinical examination by
      using the Enamel Decalcification Index (EDI) scores.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>33 subjects were prospectively recruited for the project in the MI Varnish group. These subjects were studied against a control group of 29 orthodontically treated subjects who received routine treatment and oral hygiene regimes. All subjects will be patients seeking orthodontic treatment at the Department of Orthodontics, School of Dentistry, University of Alabama at Birmingham.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Photographic records and Clinical examination</measure>
    <time_frame>Photographs were taken for 4 times at monthly intervals. Changes will be compared and assessed. The duration of the observation is an average of 4 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Photographic records will be used to determine the improvements in the white spot lesions. A standard intra-oral photographic camera will be utilized and the photographs will be taken in a light controlled environment and photographs will be captured in a pre-set photographic protocol. The Enamel decalcification index (EDI) will be used to determine the number of white spot lesions present at each time frame.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">33</enrollment>
  <condition>White Spot Lesion</condition>
  <condition>Orthodontic Treatment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MI Varnish Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>33 subjects were prospectively recruited for the project in the MI Varnish group. All subjects will be patients seeking orthodontic treatment at the Department of Orthodontics, UAB. MI Varnish were applied on their teeth initially for 4 weeks (twice) and then 3 monthly intervals.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>A control group was comprised of 29 orthodontically treated subjects who received routine treatment and oral hygiene regimes. All subjects will be patients seeking orthodontic treatment at the Department of Orthodontics, School of Dentistry, University of Alabama at Birmingham. No intervention for this group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MI Varnish</intervention_name>
    <description>MI Varnish with RECALDENT™ (CPP-ACP) enhances enamel acid resistance and boosts salivary fluoride levels. This product remains on the teeth longer than other fluoride varnishes and contains high levels of fluoride and calcium released in the oral cavity. The difference is in the RECALDENT™ (CPP-ACP), which makes MI Varnish a natural and unique choice for your patients. Casein phosphopeptides (CPP) naturally occurs in milk casein; Amorphous Calcium Phosphate (ACP), which is found in the RECALDENT™, is also the source of calcium and phosphate. In the oral cavity, CPP binds to oral surfaces such as teeth, dentin, oral mucosa and biofilm. Calcium and phosphate ions are the building blocks for healthy teeth and MI Varnish delivers bioavailable calcium and phosphate ions into the saliva.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MI Varnish Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control group</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants received routine treatment and oral hygiene regimes. No intervention for this group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients seeking orthodontic treatment and receiving routine treatment and oral
             hygiene regimes.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any medical or dental condition that in the opinion of the investigator could impact
             study results during the expected length of the study;

          -  Patient is currently using any investigational drug or any other investigational
             device;

          -  Patient plans to relocate or move within six months of enrollment.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chung H Kau, BDS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>March 2018</verification_date>
  <!-- For several months we've had both old and new date name tags                             -->
  <!-- Now, the old date names have been dropped.                                               -->
  <!-- The new date name replacements are:                                                      -->
  <!--     OLD (gone)                                        NEW (in use)                       -->
  <!--   lastchanged_date                         becomes   last_update_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_date                       becomes   study_first_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_date               becomes   results_first_submitted             -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_disposition_date   becomes   disposition_first_submitted         -->
  <study_first_submitted>February 14, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 20, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Chung How Kau</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor and Chairman</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Enamel decalcification</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>March 16, 2018</submitted>
    <returned>April 11, 2018</returned>
    <submitted>April 24, 2018</submitted>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>
