<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 11, 2018</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03147742</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INCB 18424-MA-GD-301</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03147742</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Expanded Access Program of Ruxolitinib for the Treatment of Graft-Versus-Host Disease Following Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplant</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-Label, Expanded Access Program of Ruxolitinib for the Treatment of Graft-Versus-Host Disease Following Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplant</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Incyte Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Incyte Corporation</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To provide ruxolitinib through an expanded access program for the treatment of
      graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) in United States to patients who are ineligible or unable to
      participate in any actively enrolling Incyte-sponsored clinical studies for ruxolitinib in
      the treatment of GVHD.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Available</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <expanded_access_info>
    <expanded_access_type_intermediate>Yes</expanded_access_type_intermediate>
  </expanded_access_info>
  <condition>Graft-versus-host Disease (GVHD)</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ruxolitinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Ruxolitinib starting dose level 5 mg orally, twice daily (BID). For patients with acute GVHD, the dose may be escalated to 10 mg BID.</description>
    <other_name>INCB018424</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Key Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male or female, 12 years of age or older.

          -  Have undergone an allo-HSCT from any donor source using bone marrow, peripheral blood
             stem cells, or cord blood for hematologic malignancies. Recipients of nonmyeloablative
             and myeloablative conditioning regimens are eligible.

          -  Clinically suspected all grades acute or chronic GVHD as per Minnesota-Center for
             International Blood and Marrow Transplant Research (MN-CIBMTR) criteria, that is
             refractory or intolerant to corticosteroids, occurring after allo-HSCT with any
             conditioning regimen and any anti-GVHD prophylactic program. Clinical suspicion of
             GVHD by the treating physician is also sufficient.

          -  Evidence of myeloid engraftment (eg, absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.0 × 10^9/L for 3
             consecutive days if ablative therapy was previously used). Use of growth factor
             supplementation is allowed.

          -  Evidence of platelet engraftment (ie, platelets ≥ 20 × 10^9/L).

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 to 3.

          -  Be willing to avoid pregnancy or fathering children based on 1 of the following
             criteria:

               -  Women of non-childbearing potential (ie, surgically sterile with a hysterectomy
                  and/or bilateral oophorectomy OR ≥ 12 months of amenorrhea).

               -  Woman of childbearing potential who has a negative serum pregnancy test at
                  screening and who agrees to take appropriate precautions to avoid pregnancy (with
                  at least 99% certainty) from screening through safety follow-up. Permitted
                  methods that are at least 99% effective in preventing pregnancy should be
                  communicated to the patient and their understanding confirmed.

               -  Man who agrees to take appropriate precautions to avoid fathering children (with
                  at least 99% certainty) from screening through safety follow-up. Permitted
                  methods that are at least 99% effective in preventing pregnancy should be
                  communicated to the patient and their understanding confirmed.

          -  Able to provide written informed consent and/or assent from the patient, parent, or
             guardian.

        Key Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Eligible for an existing and actively enrolling Incyte sponsored clinical trial for
             ruxolitinib for the treatment of GVHD.

          -  Patients or legal guardians unable to review and sign informed consent form.

          -  Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding, and males and females who cannot comply
             with requirements to avoid fathering a child or becoming pregnant.

          -  Patients with inadequate liver function (alanine aminotransferase above 4 × upper
             limit of normal (ULN) or direct bilirubin 4 × ULN and the laboratory abnormalities are
             considered to be due to underlying liver dysfunction) unless attributed to GVHD.

          -  Patients with end stage renal function (creatinine clearance (CrCl) &lt; 15 mL/min or
             glomerular filtration rate &lt; 15 mL/min), regardless of whether hemodialysis is
             required.

          -  Any underlying or current medical or psychiatric condition that, in the opinion of the
             treating physician, would place the patient at an unacceptable risk if he or she were
             to participate in the program.

          -  Previous allergic reactions to Janus kinase (JAK) inhibitors or excipients.

          -  Patients who are currently taking any anticancer therapy (eg, chemotherapy, radiation
             therapy, surgery, immunotherapy, biologic therapy, hormonal therapy, or tumor
             embolization).

          -  Patients taking any secondary GVHD therapy due to insufficient response/progression on
             program treatment, including but not limited to ibrutinib, filgotinib, and other
             off-label medications.

          -  Concomitant use of any JAK inhibitor.

          -  Initiating therapy with any investigational medication.

          -  Presence of an active uncontrolled infection. An active uncontrolled infection is
             defined as hemodynamic instability attributable to sepsis or new symptoms, worsening
             physical signs, or radiographic findings attributable to infection. Persisting fever
             without signs or symptoms will not be interpreted as an active uncontrolled infection.

          -  Known HIV infection.

          -  Active hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus infection that requires treatment
             or at risk for HBV reactivation. At risk for HBV reactivation is defined as hepatitis
             B surface antigen positive or anti-hepatitis B core antibody positive. Previous test
             results obtained as part of standard of care before allo-HSCT that confirm a patient
             is immune and not at risk for reactivation (ie, hepatitis B surface antigen negative,
             surface antibody positive) may be used for purposes of eligibility.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmad Naim, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Incyte Corporation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Incyte Corporation Call Center (US)</last_name>
    <phone>1.855.463.3463</phone>
    <email>medinfo@incyte.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>July 2017</verification_date>
  <!-- For several months we've had both old and new date name tags                             -->
  <!-- Now, the old date names have been dropped.                                               -->
  <!-- The new date name replacements are:                                                      -->
  <!--     OLD (gone)                                        NEW (in use)                       -->
  <!--   lastchanged_date                         becomes   last_update_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_date                       becomes   study_first_submitted               -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_date               becomes   results_first_submitted             -->
  <!--   firstreceived_results_disposition_date   becomes   disposition_first_submitted         -->
  <study_first_submitted>May 8, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 8, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 3, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 3, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 5, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ruxolitinib</keyword>
  <keyword>acute or chronic steroid-refractory GVHD</keyword>
  <keyword>hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (allo-HSCT)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>
